{"Topic": "Animals and Birds (3 pages)", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "tiple Choice G.K. Questions - Animals and Birds", "op1": "Emu", "op2": "Ostrich", "op3": "Albatross", "op4": "Siberian Crane", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which is the largest living bird on Earth?", "op1": "About 25 million years", "op2": "About 65 milion years", "op3": "About 100 million years", "op4": "About 135 million years", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "For how many years have the dinosaurs been extinct?", "op1": "Fishes", "op2": "Lizards", "op3": "Birds", "op4": "Amphibians"}, {"Question": "Darwin finches refers to a group of", "op1": "Elephant", "op2": "Whale", "op3": "Dinosaur", "op4": "Rhinoceros", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which amongst the following is the largest mammal?", "op1": "Canine", "op2": "Premolar", "op3": "Second Incisor", "op4": "Molar", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which part becomes modified as the tusk of elephant?", "op1": "Whales", "op2": "Whale sharks", "op3": "Alytes", "op4": "Draco", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following are warm-blooded animals?", "op1": "Amphibians", "op2": "Reptiles", "op3": "Birds", "op4": "Mammals", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Syrinx is the voice box in", "op1": "Refraction of sound", "op2": "Formation of beats", "op3": "Scattering", "op4": "Echo location", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which phenomenon do bats or dolphins use to find prey, predators or obstacles?", "op1": "Pigeon", "op2": "Parrot", "op3": "Humming bird", "op4": "House sparrow", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following is the smallest bird?", "op1": "Jammu and Kashmir and Himachal Pradesh only", "op2": "Jammu and Kashmir, Himachal Pradesh and Uttarakhand only", "op3": "Jammu and Kashmir, Himachal Pradesh, Uttarakhand and Arunachal Pradesh only", "op4": "Jammu and Kashmir, Himachal Pradesh, Uttarakhand, Arunachal Pradesh and Sikkim", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "The project snow Leopard to conserve the endangered species, launched by the union ministry of environment and forests covers the states of", "op1": "Salt Water Crocodile", "op2": "Sea Turtle", "op3": "Dugong", "op4": "Dolphin"}, {"Question": "Which of the following is the National Aquatic Animal of India?", "op1": "Bull, deer and eagle", "op2": "Deer and elephant", "op3": "Elephant, tiger and bull", "op4": "Horse and bull", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Among the following animals, the figures of which are found in the state emblem of India?", "op1": "Cheetah", "op2": "Jaguar", "op3": "Leopard", "op4": "Panther", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "In which one of the following animals do distinct black stripes extend from the inner corners of the eyes to the mouth?", "op1": "1 only", "op2": "1 and 2 only", "op3": "2 and 3 only", "op4": "1, 2 and 3", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Consider the following pairs", "op1": "Rann of Kutch", "op2": "Baghelkhand", "op3": "Sunderbans", "op4": "Shivaliks", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "ch of the above pairs is/are correctly matched?"}, {"Question": "e:"}, {"Question": "Pashmina shawl is made from the hair of :", "op1": "Sheep", "op2": "Goat", "op3": "Rabbit", "op4": "Yak", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which one among the following enzymes is unique in the alimentary canal of cattle?", "op1": "Cellulase", "op2": "Amylase", "op3": "Pectinase", "op4": "Driselase", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "This animal fasts for about 8 months in a year and yet is active, gives birth, and nurses its young while fasting. Name the animal.", "op1": "Polar Bear", "op2": "Frog", "op3": "Reindeer", "op4": "Lion", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following birds is the state bird of three Indian states?", "op1": "Hill Mynah", "op2": "Blue Jay (Indian Roller)", "op3": "Greater Flamingo", "op4": "Great Hornbill", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "In which of the following species does the male have mammary glands to feed milk to its young?", "op1": "Sunda flying lemur", "op2": "Blue Whale", "op3": "Polar bear", "op4": "Dayak fruit bat", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "For which one of the following snakes is the diet mainly composed of other snakes?", "op1": "Krait", "op2": "Russel's viper", "op3": "Rattlesnake", "op4": "King Cobra", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "What was the name of the first cloned sheep?", "op1": "Jolly", "op2": "Dolly", "op3": "Molly", "op4": "Polly", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which one among the following lays eggs and does not produce young ones directly?", "op1": "Echidna", "op2": "Kangaroo", "op3": "Porcupine", "op4": "Whale", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "The release of which one of the following into ponds and wells helps in controlling the mosquitoes?", "op1": "Crab", "op2": "Dogfish", "op3": "Gambusia fish", "op4": "Snail", "Answer": 3}]}